## MIKE ACORD

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

acordmike@gmail.com 1-920-224-4584 https://www.mikeacord.com

Seasoned application developer and solutions consultant with over 14 years of experience in designing, developing, and implementing database and web applications using Microsoft technologies. Specialties include C#, ASP.Net MVC, SQL Server development and administration and SharePoint deployment, development and administration. Certified in Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer: Web Applications.

## SKILLS

WEB JAVASCRIPT HTML 5 CSS LAMP MVC REST CSS

JAVASCRIPT ANGULAR.JS JQUERY BACKBONE.JS

DATABASE SQL SERVER TSQL INTEGRATION SERVICES ANALYSIS SERVICES REPORTING SERVICES

**CLOUD AZURE** 

**PROJECT AGILE TFS** 

**DEVOPS TFS TEAM CITY OCTOPUS DEPLOY** 

**SHAREPOINT ADMINISTRATION DEVELOPMENT OFFICE 365** 

## EMPLOYMENT

#### Senior Solutions Architect, Consultant, Omni Resources

2012-07 — Present

Senior Microsoft Architect, building solutions for clients

- Led team creating web-based report designer and high-performance report execution engine for a student management system
- Worked on team developing a dealer showcase website in Azure using ASP.Net MVC, web services and Backbone.JS
- Developed new data warehouse for an insurance company using SQL Server, AWS and Redshift
- Developed a flexible interview building and reporting application for a health outcome reporting company
- Managed and administrated internal systems and applications

Agile C# DevOps Javascript ASP.Net MVC SQL Server Analysis Services Integration Services SharePoint Azure Business Intelligence Office365 TFS Administration

#### SharePoint/Business Intelligence Technical Lead / Consultant,

2008-06 - 2012-06

**Heartland Business Systems (Avastone)** 

Designed and developed custom .Net, Business Intelligence and SharePoint solutions for businesses, managed technical consulting team

- Developed school teacher evaluation system in SharePoint, .Net and javascript
- Created health reporting and analytics system in ASP.Net MVC
- Designed and created school district website in SharePoint
- Developed new product workflow application in InfoPath
- Designed and developed a data warehouse on SQL Server database and Analysis Services
- Implemented numerous SharePoint installations, upgrades and custom development projects

C# Javascript ASP.Net MVC SQL Server Analysis Services Integration Services Sharepoint Business Intelligence

#### **Business Intelligence Consultant, Fujitsu Consulting**

2006-08 - 2008-04

Senior BI Consultant building data integration solutions

- Designed and developed data migration strategy from legacy system using Integration Services
- Created real-time data integration from new web application back to legacy mainframe
- Developed reporting services reports

SSIS SQL Server ASP.Net C# Reporting Services

#### **Business Intelligence Consultant, Compuware**

2005-05 - 2006-07

SQL Server development consulting

- Developed and optimized SQL Server applications
- Developed bill of materials cost reporting application in MS Access
- Developed Crystal Reports

**SQL Server MS Access Crystal Reports** 

### Systems Analyst, DRS Power & Control Technologies

2001-08 - 2005-08

Internal application development and support

- Gathered and analyzed business requirements
- Used application development methodologies to create internal business applications Led cross-functional, multi-site teams to facilitate and improve business processes
- Created an Operational Data Store from mainframe data and Crystal Reports to the analyze data

SQL Server DTS ASP VB.Net

Milwaukee

# EDUCATION

MS in Management-Electronic Business, University of Wisconsin-

2002-08 - 2003-12

1998-08 - 2002-05BS in Business and Computer Systems, International Business, Milwaukee School of Engineering